Guide to the Eyes of Texas television show episodes and summaries collection, 1978-2009 MS 170
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Eyes of Texas television show episodes and summaries collection
1979-2009
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
KPRC-TV (Television station: Houston, Tex.).
MS 170
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box of episode summaries. DVD's of episodes cataloged separately)
29.2 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_001
23.9 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_002
29.8 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_003
30.3 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_004
29.3 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_005
29.9 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_006
25.4 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_007
10.3 Gigabytes Nearline access: MS0170aip_008
Copies of annotated typewritten summaries of Eyes of Texas television episodes 1979-1993 and 2007-2009 as prepared by KPRC-TV, and copies of those episodes in DVD format, beginning Sept. 02, 1978.
Historical Sketch
The Eyes of Texas television show was created by director Ray Miller at Houston's KPRC-TV and first aired in June 1969. After Ray Miler retired, KPRC-TV Houston news anchor Ron Stone took over as host. The show ran for 29 years, coming to a halt in 1998. In 2007, KPRC began a new series of Eyes of Texas (see http://www.click2houston.com/eyesoftexas/index.html).
Curious about the Von Minden Hotel and Theater in Schulenburg, Texas' longest operating combination hotel and theater? What about Camp Winiwaca in Rosebud? Did you know Mr. J. Moore, fiddle restorer, in Taylor? The Eyes of Texas show visited landmarks, holes in the wall, everyday folks – a delightful variety of things Texan.
All of the original Eyes of Texas shows from 1969-1978 were shot on film and to date, have not been transferred to tape or DVD. Those early shows on film are at KPRC-TV, not available at Rice University. However many of these stories reappear in later episodes beginning in 1978 and are available at Rice University.
Episodes began to be numbered in 1978, starting with episode 1, Sept. 2, 1978.
Scope and Contents
Copies of annotated typewritten summaries of Eyes of Texas television episodes 1978-1993 and 2007-2009 as prepared by KPRC-TV, and copies of episodes in DVD format, beginning Sept. 02, 1978 through 1992, and 2007-2009, with some missing episodes as noted below.
To access the episodes here on DVD, request call # F 391.2 .E93 ) followed by the episode number and (WRC). For example, F 391.2 .E93 episode 001 (WRC).
Episodes missing from the DVD set are:
Episodes 25-27 (1979)
Episodes 43-59 (1979)
Episodes 65-67 (1980)
Episode 83 (1980)
Episodes 102-104 (1981)
Episodes 114-119 (1981)
Episodes 132-137 (1981)
Episodes 150-152 (1982)
Episodes 157-160 (1982)
Episodes 164-172 (1982)
Episodes 190-192 (1983)
Episodes 197-199 (1983)
Episodes 212-214 (1983)
Episodes 233-235 (1984)
Episode 242 (1984)
Episodes 246-248 (1984)
Episode 254 (1984)
15th anniversary show (August 06, 1984)
Episodes 259-261 (1985)
Episodes 271-276 (1985)
Episodes 280-282 (1985)
Episodes 292-294 (1986)
Episodes 317-319 (1986)
Episodes 326-328 (1986)
Episodes 365-368 (1987-1988)
Episodes 375-380 (1988)
Episodes 387-391 (1988)
Episodes 395-400 (1988)
Episodes 404-409 (1989)
Episodes 428-430 (1989)
Episodes 445-450 (1990)
Episodes 463-468 (1990)
Episodes 475-480 (1990-1991)
All episodes missing for 1993
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Provenance
Donated to Rice by Pat Schwab on behalf of KPRC-TV/DT, a Post – Newsweek station, in 2009.
Related Material
A specially published DVD set of selected Eyes of Texas episodes published as "Texas: Our Texas with Ray Miller" was donated in 2006-2007. These DVDs are thematically organized. Themes include Ranchers and Ranching (F391.3 .T393 2002), Odd Jobs (F386 .T386 2007), Railroads (F386 .T387 2007), Route 66 (F386 .T39 2006), and Oil Men and the Oil Business (F386 .T38 2006).
Index Terms
Subjects
Business; Folklore
Document Types
videotapes
Places
Texas -- History
- 1978 episodes, 227182
  - KPRC's summary of 1978 episodes, 227200 (Folder 1)
  - Sept. 2, 1978: Moon Players – White Rock, Dallas / Mormon Hill, Burnet / Fort Duncan, Eagle Pass / Buck Schiwetz – Artist, Hunt / Jose Navarro – Texas, San Antonio, 227199 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 001:)
  - Sept. 9, 1978: Search for La Salle's Ships, Matagorda / Fannie Kelly-Turkens, Rusk / Spanish Governor's Palace, San Antonio / Sutton-Taylor Feud, Cuero, 227198 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 002:)
  - Sept. 16, 1978: Nimitz Center, Fredericksburg / Omen, Texas / John Biggers – Artist, Houston/ La Lomita Mission, Penitus, 227197 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 003:)
  - Sept. 23, 1978: FDR Visits Galveston, May 11, 1937; Galveston Mayor Adrian F. Levy / Alabama Coushatta Drama, Livingston / Gladys Farek Cookie Shop, Cistern / Decatur, Wise Co., 227196 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 004:)
  - Sept. 30, 1978: Prairie View A&M Centennial 1976 / Minna Kott – Crochet, Fredericksburg / Jim Butcher – Flatonia Depot Salvage / UT Alumni Band and Halftime / Faust Hotel, New Braunfels, 227195 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 005)
  - Oct. 7, 1978: Jim Cummings – Bull Dozers, San Marcos / Old San Antonio Depot; Efraim Abrmoff / Matt Krey – Falconer, Nacogdoches / The Champion Newspaper, Center; Bob Pinkston / Galipp – Mish Mash Mall, Schulenburg, 227194 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 006)
  - October 14, 1978: J. Moore – Fiddle Restorer, Taylor / Camel Corps, Camp Verde; Merrill Doyle / Mary Allen College - Crocket; Daisy Pender / Jimmy Porter – Baseball, Porter / Lackey Sawmill, Near Kerrville, 227193 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 007)
  - October 28, 1978: Von Minden Hotel and Theater, Schulenburg / Jesus Y Marie Ranch, Hebronville; Tom Allen / JM Murphy – Woodcarver, San Antonio / Atkins' Calvert Hotel, Calvert; Philip Atkins / Caverns of Sonora, 227192 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 008)
  - Nov. 4, 1978: Camp Winiwaca, Rosebud / Old Belton mansions, Belton / Kelly Air Force Base Photo Mural / Railroad Tie Changing, Somerville and Alvin / Miller's Store and BBQ, Waelder, 227191 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 009)
  - Nov. 11, 1978: Fatted Calf Restaurant, Valley View / Belton Dam Mural, Belton Lake / Mentone-Loving Co. (Least Pop. US) / Christman's – Mason, Quilter, Anderson / Spradley-Telephones, McGregor, 227190 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 010)
  - Nov. 18, 1978: Whooping Cranes, Aransas Refuge / Cheapside, Texas / Repertory Theater of America, Rockport / Edna G. White – Pioneer Pilot, Roanoke / Mission Tejas St. Park, Weches, 227189 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 011)
  - Nov. 25, 1978: Texas Navy / Reeves – Automatic Bull, Garland / J.S. Cullinan – Oilman, Corsicana / Buck's – Lone Star Tavern, Waco / San Felipe Springs, Del Rio, 227188 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 012)
  - Dec. 2, 1978: Texas Historical Markers, San Antonio / Chihuahuan Desert Research, Alpine / Mexican Invasion-San Ignacio / Nichols-Farmers Co-op, Victoria / San Antonio Missions, 227187 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 013)
  - Dec. 9, 1978: CP Johnson-Cow Dogs, Bastrop / St. Benedict's Farm, Waelder / Goobers of Grapeland / Della Wynn-Doll Maker, Sunset / Hot Springs-Big Bend, 227186 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 014)
  - Dec. 16, 1978: Nautical Archaeologists, TX A&M / Schaper Dairy, Galveston / Dr. Mario Ramirez-Family Dr, Roma / Former Adamcik Cafe, Schulenburg / First Monday, Canton, 227185 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 015)
  - Dec. 23, 1978: Calliham Becomes Reservoir / Dawson-Toy Trains, San Antonio / Lowell Fulsom-Guitarist, Houston / Marine Military Academy, Harlingen / Nelius-Tool Museum, Bellville, 227184 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 016)
  - Dec. 30, 1978: TX DOT-Highway Markers / TX Wildcatters / Glenn McCarthy-Wildcatter, Houston / Dallas Visitor & Convention Ctr, 227183 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 017)
- 1979 episodes, 227140
  - KPRC's summary of 1979 episodes, 227181 (Folder 2)
  - Jan. 6, 1979: Cherokee Nation/Island, Brownsville / H Marshall-Pushup Champ, San Antonio / Cy Stapleton-Old Newspapers, Houston / Eckhardt-Log Cabin, Harris Co. / Anderson Tx-Home Tour, 227180 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 018)
  - Jan. 13, 1979: O Henry & His San Antonio House / Taylor- Harpsicord Builder, Houston / Only Union Monument-Comfort / Brown-Abbey Wedding Chapel, Austin / McKittrick Canyon, Guadalupe Mts., 227179 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 019)
  - Jan. 20, 1979: Isham-Underground House, Energy / Malm-Scale Brass RR Builder, Crane's Mill / Colonel Edward House, Austin / Catchings-Talents of TX, Yorktown / St. Anthony Hotel, San Antonio, 227178 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 020)
  - Jan. 27, 1979: UT Ancient Coin Collection, Austin / Cox's Build Log Cabin, Broaddus / Reg Robbins-Aviator, Fort Worth / Jimmy Walker-Collector, Leigh / Winedale Historical Center, 227177 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 021)
  - Feb. 3, 1979: Texas Longhorns, Fashing; Bob Thonhoff / Sahawe Indian Dancers, Uvalde; Bill Dillahunty / J Peterson-Pipe Organs, Fort Worth / Oren Reeves-Mule Skinner, Pittsburg / Socorro Texas, 227176 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 022)
  - Feb. 10, 1979: A&M Vet School, College Station / Tieman-Music House, Yorktown / Paramount Theater, Austin / Uncertain Texas, Wayne Bailey / Meyersville Lutheran Church, 227175 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 023)
  - Feb. 17, 1979: The Strand, Galveston / Amon Carter, Fort Worth / S Gray-Rock Carver, Weimar / Jim White-Bootmaker, Angleton / Menger Hotel, San Antonio, 227174 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 024)
  - Feb. 24, 1979: Quilting Society, Independence Mound / Fort Clark, Bracketville / C.H. Davidson House, Livingston / Stagecoach Inn, Salado / Stark Museum, Orange, 227173 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 025)
  - March 3, 1979: Rattlesnake Huntress, Mason County / Frederic Remington, Artist / James lay House, Halletsville / Bottle Collector, Houston / Sabinal Canyon, 227172 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 026)
  - March 10, 1979: San Jacinto Monument, Houston / New Camden, Livingston / Mockingbirds / Amy Gray, Piano Player Gustine / Hotel Blessing, Blessing, 227171 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 027)
  - March 17, 1979: Wm. Gebhardt Chili, New Braunfels / S Latham-Carriage Collector, Douglassville / Mt. Zion Baptist Church, Edgar / Gail Bordon, Jr. / Peach Blossoms, Fredericksburg, 227170 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 028)
  - March 24, 1979: Samuel Morse - Telegraph / Hardscramble Ranger Station, Seguin / Vaughn-TX Rockers, Woodville / Armstrong-Browning Library, Waco / Fragrance Garden, Beaumont, 227169 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 029)
  - March 31, 1979: Texas Made Cars / Lynchburg Ferry, Lynchburg-LaPorte / Angelo's Shell Shop, Galveston / Briscoe's 1st State Bank, Uvalde / Gorman Falls, San Saba Co., 227168 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 030)
  - April 7, 1979: Round Mountain Stagecoach Inn, Blanco / Kallison's Western Store, San Antonio / Zimmerscheidt Schoolhouse, Columbus / Sedlar Farm-'Special' Sheep, Canyon Lake / State's Oldest Stone Fort, Nacogdoches, 227167 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 031)
  - April 14, 1979: Cattle Brands-A&M, College Station / Krieger-Dirigible Man, Dallas / Cottonseed Oil Mill, Riverside / Broomstick Factory, Diboll / Shafter Texas, 227166 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 032)
  - April 21, 1979: Private Bank of Leroy / Royce Roberts-Bluebonnet Painter, Burnet Co / Tornado Home Warning Sys, Plainview / Binford Weaver-Bee Keeper, Navasota / Wildflowers of Big Bend, 227165 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 033)
  - April 28, 1979: Guion-Composer "Home On Range" / Waller Co Museum, Brookshire / Otto Raab-Blacksmith, Nursery / Patillo House, Vidor / El Paisano Hotel, Marfa, 227164 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 034)
  - May 5, 1979: NASA-Johnson Space Ctr, Houston / Lloyd Mitchell-Spurs, Gatesville / Ed Krenek-Dulcimer, Wallis / John Sinclair-"Eyes of Texas" Composer / Fort Worth Nature Ctr & Refuge, 227163 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 035)
  - May 12, 1979: Goodspeed-Pigeons/Photos, San Antonio / J Frank Dobie-Paisano Ranch, Austin / Wallisville Texas / Stagecoach History, Bracketville & Marshall, 227162 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 036)
  - May 19, 1979: Plaza Nacional Hotel, San Antonio; Martha Buchanan Lucero / Gussie Nell Davis-Kilgore Rangerettes / Silver Texas / Stein Lumber Co, Fredericksburg / Blum Building-Strand, Galveston, Wentletrap Restaurant, 227161 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 037)
  - May 26, 1979: Tony Lama Boots, El Paso / Doan's Trading Post, Vernon / Tranquility Park, Houston / San Marcos Academy / Abram Alley Cabin, Columbus, 227160 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 038)
  - June 2, 1979: Old Ursaline Academy, San Antonio / Fort Velasco, Freeport / San Elizario, Near El Paso / John Henry Faulk, Madisonville / Coupland Texas, 227159 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 039)
  - Sept. 1, 1979: J. Francis-Natural Foods, Atlanta / Joe Burch-Corviar Collector, Dallas / D'Hanis, Texas / Pecos Pate Boone, Cristoval / Bean-Whitehead Museum, Del Rio, 227158 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 040)
  - Sept. 8, 1979: R Hugman-Riverwalk, San Antonio / Stone-Feed Mill Restaurant, Ector / Z Childress-Remembers, Haslam / Stecher-Stained Glass, Woodville / Old City Park, Dallas, 227157 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 041)
  - Sept. 15, 1979: Dailey-Tanning Booths, Dallas / B Tabor-Chainsaw Carver, Whiteright / Bloys Camp Meeting, Fort Davis / R Geisler-Handmade Cars, Midland / Steve Spence - Settlement Inn, Leon Springs, 227156 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 042)
  - Sept. 22, 1979: R. Clements - Symphony Square, Austin / R. Monroe - Theater Organist, Beaumont / G. Holmes - Byers, Texas Telephone Man / G. Autrey, J. Garcia - Branding Iron Restaurant, Del Rio / Centennial House, Corpus Christi, 227155 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 043)
  - Sept. 29, 1979: John Robert Prude - Prude Ranch, Fort Davis / World's Smallest Skyscraper, Wichita Falls / Ed McMahon - Saddle and Spur Collector, Houston / Crash at Crush, Central Texas / Presidential Museum, Odessa, 227154 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 044)
  - Oct. 6, 1979: Peele - Peanut Brittle Factory, Hamilton / Ward - Catarina, Texas / Burkhart - Harp Maker, Corsicana / Lester - Hamlin Gardens, Jacksonville / Buckner - Pecos Museum and June Fest, 227153 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 045)
  - Oct 13, 1979: Bill Hooper - Circus School, Mesquite / Old Main, Waco / Goodson's Cafe, Tomball / Jack Specht - Filmmaker, Wichita Falls and Three Rivers / Smokey Lehnert and Miguel Benavides - Pecos to Seminole Canyons, 227152 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 046)
  - Oct. 20, 1979: Bateman - Moonlight Towers, Austin / Zahn - Belly Dancer, Tyler / Breaux - Toy Collector, Freeport; Faulk - John Avery Lomax / Field, Whitson - Stonewall Saloon Museum, St. Jo, 227151 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 047)
  - Oct. 27, 1979: Bean - Preserving History in East Texas / Saunders, Cronfel - Costumes from the Arab World, Houston / Sukup - Rosebud Blacksmith / Cullum - Happy Jazz Band, San Antonio / Judge Mead's Collection, Miami, 227150 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 048)
  - Nov. 3, 1979: Gormeen Kamin - Open Door, Victoria / Nan McGarity - Woodcarver-Waterwitch, Avinger / Gaston Boykin - Old Cora Courthouse, Comanche County / Stanley Marsh - Amarillo / Cavalry Museum, El Paso, 227149 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 049)
  - Nov. 10, 1979: Adolph Schedule, Jimmy Alexander - Rice Farming, Southeast Texas / Floyd Tillman - Central Texas / Laura Powell, Mary Rosborough - Scottsville, Texas / Dr. Joel Shiner - Aquarena Springs Excavation, Dallas and San Marcos / Longhorn Museum, Pleasanton, 227148 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 050)
  - Nov. 17, 1979: Wayne Shifflet - Prarie Chicken Refuge, League City and Eagle Lake / Anahuac, Texas / Katherine Haines, Jack Baskin - Railroad Museum, Temple / Carnegie library, Ballinger / Frank Weise Jr. - Matterhorn, Salado, 227147 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 051)
  - Nov. 24, 1979: Harrison, Anderson, Marks, Wernex - Motorcycle Workshop, Livingston / Binkley - Dr. John Binkley, Del Rio / Dunnam - Old Victoria Courthouse / Merkimer - Mr. Cheerleader, Dallas / Stratman - Shiner Opera House, 227146 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 052)
  - Dec. 1, 1979: Ron Barbutti - Preserving Downton, San Angelo / Earl Cabaniss - Iron Man of Saldo / Carol Bade - Church Banner Lady, Fredericksburg / Shorty Pechacek - Doll House Builder, Port Lavaca / Nick Rodes, James Elmo Rosier - Big Thicket Museum, Saratoga, 227145 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 053)
  - Dec. 8, 1979: Dr. Sherman Lesene - Candle Factory, Georgetown / Elouise moore - Kitchen Band, Teague / Felix Hernandez, Frank Smith - Chamizal, El Paso / Ed Chavez - Model Plane Builder, San Antonio / John Bonds - Lone Star Hiking Trail, Huntsville, 227144 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 054)
  - Dec. 15, 1979: Dick Witherell - St. Regis Paper Co, Lufkin / Beck - Cotton Gin, Florence / Prarie Dog Town, Odessa / Margaret Walberg - Old Courthouse, Corpus Christi / John Ahrns, John Watson - Westcave Preserve, Austin, 227143 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 055)
  - Dec. 22, 1979: Jerry Crisp - Highway Department Nursery, Stockdale / Clarence Thurston McLaughlin - Diamond M Museum, Synder / Lowell Wilkes - Hubbard, Texas / Dickens on the Strand, Galveston / Fall in East Texas, 227142 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 056)
  - Dec. 29, 1979: Simmons, Graff, Gregory - Texas State Teachers Association, Mexia / Glickman - Record Shop, Big Spring / Schweers, Wentz - Medina County Museum, Hondo / Dick, Mason - Highland Games, Salado, 227141 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 057)
- 1980 episodes, 227099
  - KPRC's summary of 1980 episodes, 227139 (Folder 3)
  - Jan. 5, 1980: Gates, Thompson - East Texas Yamboree, Gilmer / Harrison - Santa Fe Trail, Panhandle / Windsor - Roseland Plantation, Tyler / Hanks - Rattlesnake Man / Wright - Reuster Building, San Antonio, 227138 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 058)
  - Jan. 12, 1980: Hester, Ivey - Alamo Dig, San Antonio / Smith - Water Wheel Expert, Houston / Walker - Callahan County Museum, Baird / Hewitt - Crochet Man, Glendale / Riesel-Leveritt, Jones - Sydnor-Powhaten House, Galveston, 227137 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 059)
  - Jan. 19, 1980: Broom, Naquin-Worm Fertilizer, Houston / Moore-Doll Houses, Abilene / Reid - Shortest TX Highway, Huntsville / Wilson-Lariat Maker, Marshall / Podhora-Wildflower Artist, Port Lavaca, 227136 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 060)
  - Jan. 26, 1980: Hammer - Ambassador College, Big Sandy / Reveley-Dentist/Undertaker, San Antonio / Sanders, Drennan - Six Shooter Junction, Hempstead / Torok & Redd-Piney Woods Music / Burgon-Po Po Restaurant, Welfare, 227135 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 061)
  - Feb. 2, 1980: Garcia, West, Garcia - Hacienda Records, Corpus Christi / Doc Hestand - Anson / W True-Tool Collector, Weimar / Luther Fore-Carpenter, Alazan / Lessesne - Mar Jon Candles, Georgetown, 227134 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 062)
  - Feb. 9, 1980: Betts, Klein - Franklin Savings Preservation, Austin / McBroom-Log Cabins, Rusk / Fred Brown-Parakeets, Clyde / Lajos Markos-Artist, Houston / Abbott - Clifton by the Sea, Baycliff, 227133 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 063)
  - Feb. 15, 1980: Weaver - Ross Volunteers, Texas A&M / K Wood-Victrolas, Nacogdoches / Camp Logan-WWI, Houston / Straley Allsup-Fiddler, Gustine / Pool - Christ the King Church, Ft Worth, 227132 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 064)
  - Feb. 23, 1980: Dato - Fort Worth Light Bulb / Blue - Ostritches at Gustine / Ansley - Hungerford, Texas / Agnor - Chili Man, Marshall / Fort Lancaster, Crockett County, 227131 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 065)
  - March 1, 1980: Horchow - King of the Catalogs, Dallas / Holton - Music Box Man, Houston / Robinson, Walker - Stages Stops at Nome / Rattlesnake Bomber Base, Pyote / Garrett - Cotton Gin Restaurant, Brookshire, 227130 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 066)
  - March 8, 1980: Tolleson, Chambers - Blimp Base, Spring / More - Bird Egg Collector, Vernon / Via - Walking Cane Man, Kingsville / Mehren - Mehren House, San Antonio / Northington - Egypt, 227129 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 067)
  - March 15, 1980: Schaer-Crawfish Farm, Dannevang / Ruby Purcell, Buffalo Gap / Boynton-Posters, Houston / Camp Holland, Valentine / Bateman - N. Chaparral St., Corpus Christi, 227128 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 068)
  - March 22, 1980: Roberts-Gasohol Farmer, Mereta / Birds of Sugar Land / Morrison - Texas Shortline Railroads / Davis-Sea Shells, Beaumont / Jim Young-Blacksmith, Goliad, 227127 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 069)
  - March 29, 1980: Decoty Coffee Co., San Angelo / Egg Brothers Store, Meyersville / Marek-Boat Builder, Port Aransas / Bramblett, Dryden - Snow Monkey Ranch, Laredo / Fort Inglish, Bonham, 227126 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 070)
  - April 05, 1980: Slim Singleton-Windmills, San Angelo / Ed Eakin-Texana Publisher, Burnet / Boll Weevil Railroad, Teague / Smith - Sea Rim Airboat Tour, Sabine Pass / Fort McKavett, Menard Co., 227125 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 071)
  - April 12, 1980: Teas Nursery, Bellaire / V. Cornelius-Menu King, Eastland / J Carroll-Custer Collector, Bryan / Seybold--Horseshoe School, Mineral Wells / Republic Rio Grande Museum, Loredo, 227124 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 072)
  - April 19, 1980: Astroworld Trainees, Houston / Bering-Log Cabin-Duchesne Aca., Houston / B Bell-Silversmith, Fredericksburg / Rathwick - Indian Cliffs Ranch, El Paso / Rusk City Park & RR, Rusk, 227123 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 073)
  - April 26, 1980: Baylor U-1st Site, Independence / Saldivar - Tex-Mex/Cohunta Music, San Antonio / Wild Azalea Canyons, Burkville / Weinheimer-Hunting Trophys, El Campo / Kate C Talbot-Chilton House, Goliad, 227122 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 074)
  - May 03, 1980: M Gammage-Texas Hatters, Austin / EB Greer-Shanghai Pierce, Victoria / Dogtown, Tilden / Grayson College, Whitewright / Star of Republic Museum-WOB, 227121 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 075)
  - May 10, 1980: Bales - Scholz's Beer Garden, Austin / Houses on Pecan Street, Bastrop / Bailey-Sydney Island, Bridge City / Historical Look at Texas Flags / Ochiai - Japanese Art Museum, Corpus, 227120 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 076)
  - May 17, 1980: Yanniell-Earth Stoves, Burnet / Randolph Airforce Base, San Antonio / Reyckert-Leathercraft, Beeville / Cruthirds-Cap Collector, Kuntz / Sweetwater Museum, 227119 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 077)
  - May 24, 1980: Fawn Tagging, Bay City / Mom Pryor-Phi Gamma Delta, Austin / Sammy Sunshine-Arch, San Augustine / Prairie Dog Town, Lubbock / Blazimar Hotel, Taylor, 227118 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 078)
  - May 31, 1980: Chuck Wagon Gang, Odessa / The Schreiners, Kerrville / Hot Wells Hotel, San Antonio / Pool Cue Maker, Houston / Highlands Mansion, Marlin, 227117 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 079)
  - Sept. 06, 1980: J Newman-Gator Artist, Beaumont / Lauderdale - Puddin Hill Fruitcakes, Greenville / Watt Matthews-Princeton, Albany / Texas Water Safari:San Marcos / Sea Drift / Adobe Walls, Stinnett, 227116 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 080)
  - Sept. 20, 1980: Glasscock, Wednford-Old Human Remains, Midland / Gillien-Hog Butchering, Kenefick / Jesse 'Bear' Hollis, Marathon / Schreiner- Y.O. Ranch, Hill Country / Historic Mason Texas, 227115 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 082)
  - Sept. 27, 1980: Hartin - Bluegrass Music School, Levelland / Joines - Pud's Place, Glen Fora / Welder Wildlife Refuge, Sinton / Oasis Foundation, Odessa / Fort Stockton Water Carnival, 227114 (Folder -, Episode DVD Episode 083)